xritephoto.com 2017-12-22

# X-Rite: Privacy Policy

X-Rite has created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate our commitment to privacy. Your right to privacy and data security is our primary concern.

When you visit and/or use an X-Rite website ("Site"), we strive to help you maintain control over your personal data. Below are the guidelines we use for protecting the information you provide us during a visit to and/or use of our Site.

  * INFORMATION GATHERING AND USAGE
  * COOKIES
  * MANAGING YOUR INFORMATION
  * SECURITY
  * OPTING OUT
  * CONTACT US
  * CHANGES IN THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT

### INFORMATION GATHERING AND USAGE

**Your personal data**

We intend to give you as much control as reasonably possible over your personal data. In general, you can visit our Site without revealing your personal data. This includes information which can be used to identify you, such as your name, email address, telephone numbers, postal address, credit card information, job function, industry, product application, contact preferences or experience with our products.

There are times, however, when we may need information from you in order to best service your needs. If you wish to order or request products, services, or information from us through the Site, including registering for various services that may be available, you may be required to share certain personal data with us so that we can process your order or request. We also may use this personal data for other business purposes, such as to invite you to participate in surveys or notify you about special promotions for our products. We generally collect this information at the time of registering to use our Site, subscribing to our services, posting materials, or requesting further services.

We also collect other information that is not linked to your personal data such as your Internet Protocol ("IP") address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Site.

**Information sharing**

We may share the personal data that you provide to us among our affiliates, partner companies and organizations that are responsible in whole or in part for processing or fulfilling your order or request, marketing our products, and to any successor to our business.

We will not otherwise use, share, disseminate, publish or disclose your personal data (except as may reasonably be required in response to litigation, investigations or other legally required disclosures).

**Links to third-party websites**

Our Site may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our Site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such websites as these websites are not governed by this Privacy Policy. You should always be sure to exercise caution and read the privacy policy applicable to the website in question.

**Message boards/forums**

This Site may make forums and message boards available to you. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal data.

**Electronic newsletters**

We offer various free electronic newsletters. We do not spam, never sell or rent email addresses, and there's an easy unsubscribe in every email you'll receive.

**Contests**

We sometimes offer contests on our Site. Participation in these contests requires that you provide us with certain personal data. At a minimum, the required information includes name and email address. In some cases, the entrant must answer mandatory survey questions about a range of technical interests and personal data. The information gathered in the entry form is used to verify the entrant's identity and eligibility, to contact winners or prize recipients, and to market and sell our products. As the rules and terms of each contest can vary, all information pertaining to a specific contest is clearly posted on our Site during the event.

**Forward to a friend feature**

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our Site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. Your email address will appear as the sender of the email and we will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Site. Both your email address and the recipient's email address will not be used for any other purpose except to facilitate the sending of this one-time email to your friend.

**Log files**

Like most standard websites, we use log files to automatically log information such as IP addresses, browser type, internet service provider ("ISP"), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. We log this information to manage traffic loads, identify the content most commonly accessed and determine information technology requirements for providing reliable service, or other web management, deployment, tracking, maintenance and similar activities. We do not use this information to identify you.

**Where we store your personal data**

We may transfer your personal data to, or store it at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who works for us, for our affiliates, or for one of our suppliers. Our staff may be engaged in, among other things, the provision of services, fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the delivery of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storage, or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy including: (i) diligently choosing third party service providers, and (ii) requiring, via appropriate contract or otherwise, that any third party service providers or affiliates maintain adequate technical and organizational security measures to safeguard your personal information, and to process personal information only as instructed by us in accordance with applicable law and for no other purposes. Such protections of cross-border transfers of personal information will be based on a mechanism approved by the European Commission as providing adequate protection. From time to time, this may include, where valid and appropriate, certification to US/EU Safe Harbor Privacy Principles published by the US Department of Commerce or an equivalent, succeeding bi-lateral agreement between the US and the European Union that ensures an equivalent level of data protection in the US ("Safe Harbor" or equivalent), or a data transfer agreement based on the EU Commission standard contractual clauses for the transfer of data to third countries.

### COOKIES

Cookies and other tracking technologies (such as web beacons) are used on this Site and/or in our communications to enhance your experience by allowing us to tailor our content based on your interests, and distinguish you from other users of our Site. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers, without any personal data, which we store on your browser or the hard drive of your device. A cookie can contain information, such as a user ID or preferences, which the Site uses to personalize content, track the pages you've visited, or to save your password so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit our Site. We do not track your personal data through cookies, unless you choose to provide this information to us, for example, by registering or logging on to our Site.

**We use the following cookies:**

  * **Strictly necessary cookies**. These are cookies or other tracking mechanisms necessary to make our Site function as intended. They include cookies which enable you to use a shopping cart.
  * **Analytical/performance cookies**. They allow us to recognize and count the number of visitors to our Site and to see how visitors move around our Site when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our Site works by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
  * **Functionality cookies**. These cookies enable us to personalize our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences. They may also be used to recognize you when you return to our Site.

You can also adjust your browser settings to receive a message every time a cookie is installed on your computer or to prevent their installation altogether. Although rejection of cookies will not interfere with your ability to interact with most of our Site, you will need to accept cookies if you choose to enter areas of our Site that require registration or login. Certain other functions and/or services might be unavailable to you if you reject cookies altogether.

Please note that some of our business partners and software vendors do use cookies on our Site (e.g., for website analytics purposes). While we strive to protect the personal data of our Site users and thoroughly review the security and privacy practices of our Site partners, we have no access to or control over these cookies. As such, this Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by us only and does not cover the use of cookies by any business partners or software vendors.

### MANAGING YOUR INFORMATION

You may at any time request access to a summary of your personal data held by us, and request corrections or updates to that information. We will make reasonable efforts to respond promptly to such requests for information in accordance with local laws. Our response to such requests may be limited to information under our direct control.

Please notify us of any changes in your name, address, title, telephone number or e-mail address. You can correct your personal data by contacting us in accordance with the ‘CONTACT US’ section to request changes. You may ask to have the information on your account deleted or removed; however, because we keep track of certain transaction information, such as past purchases, and other similar information, for legal compliance purposes, we may not be able to delete certain information. If information we hold appears to be inaccurate we will block its use until the information is corrected.

### SECURITY

**Security measures**

We limit access to your personal data to only include our employees and third-party agents, who we reasonably believe need to have access to your information to provide you with the information or services you request from us. The Site has security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, we use industry standards, such as Secure Socket Layers ("SSL") technology, to help safeguard against such occurrences. In certain areas, the information passed between your browser and our system is encrypted with SSL technology to create a protected connection between you and our Site to ensure confidentiality. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure, therefore we will strive to protect your personal data through commercially acceptable means If you have any questions about security on our Site, you can contact us via email or please send mail to the addresses identified in the 'CONTACT US' section below.

**Children's privacy protection**

This Site does not target and is not intended for children under the age of 13. This Site will not knowingly collect personal data from children, and will delete such data upon discovery.

### OPTING OUT

If you do not wish to receive certain communications from us, our affiliates, or representatives, you may opt out by: (1) declining the service offered when registering, or at other information collection points on the Site, (2) informing us via email or by sending mail to the addresses identified in the 'CONTACT US' section that you no longer wish to receive such communications, or (3) following the instructions that we include in each of our communications. We will comply with all requests unless such communications by us are required by law, or do not require your consent under applicable laws. Please note, if you opt out of certain communications, you may not be able to access certain products or services.

### CONTACT US

For Privacy Policy questions, email us at the address provided at http://www.xrite.com/ContactUs or via postal mail at:

**Addrress:** | **X-Rite, Inc.**  
3100 44th Street, SE  
Grand Rapids, MI 49512  
Attn: Vicky Schott  
---|---  

### CHANGES IN THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT

This Privacy Policy was last updated on October 28, 2016. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will make updates to this Privacy Policy, and any other places we deem appropriate. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.
